嘿 各位 我们来到徒步湾大饭店了
Okay, ladies and gents, Walkabout Creek Hotel.
这是我们进入内陆前的最后休闲时光了
Last chance for a coldie before we hit the outback.
日安 各位我是你们的女房东
G'day, all. I'm your hostess.
你们可以称呼我"鲁比"或"亲爱的" 但切记不要错过早餐时间
You can call me Ruby or love or anything, but never late for breakfast.
诸位 你们爱吃点什么?
And what's your pleasure, folks?
杜松子酒和苏打水 再来杯女士喝的葡萄酒
Gin and tonic, please, and a Pims for the lady.
好咧 松子酒 苏打水和葡萄酒
不对 我要的是一杯松子酒 加苏打水和一杯葡萄酒
No, I asked for a gin and tonic and a Pims.
啊 对 但那只是随便问问而已
Yeah, well, there's no harm in asking.
来两杯啤酒好了
Couple of beers will be just fine.
那就对了 老伙计
That's the ticket, old mate.
- 你好 纳基 - 日安 苏
- Hey, Nugget. - G'day, Sue.
- 米克在哪? - 我们接到陆军游骑兵的紧急电话
- Where's Mick? - We got a panic call from the Rangers.
他们在它瓦布尔潭里发现了一条巨鳄
They spotted a huge croc in the Tarrabool swimming hole.
老实说 我们以抛硬币来决定 谁去抓它 结果米克赢了
Actually, we tossed a coin to see who'd catch it, and Mick won.
- 然后他独个儿去了? - 不
- He went after it alone, did he? - No.
杰科 杰克逊打算去那儿找他
Jacko Jackson's gonna meet him out there.
你也知道杰科是本地的第二捕鳄高手
And Jacko, as you know, is the second best crocodile man in the territory.
那你就不必担心了 亲爱的
So you got no worries, love.
我是担心我需要米克去接米奇放学
My only worry is I need Mick to pick Mikey up after school.
这我跟他说过了 如果米克一直和鳄鱼纠缠不清
I'll tell Mick for you. If he gets tied up with that croc,
- 我会去接小家伙的 - 谢谢
- I'll pick up the young fella myself. - Thanks.
依我之见 你才是第二捕鳄高手
I thought you were the second best crocodile hunter.
- 喔 关于这个 - 啊 他谦虚罢了
- Oh, well. - Oh, he's just modest.
你知道吗? 他也是百里挑一的
He's one of the best, you know?
苏 米克有什么意外的话 我一定会两肋插刀的
Hey, Sue. If anything ever happens to Mick, I'm gonna come courtin'.
不 让我们祈祷米奇平安无事吧
Well, let's just hope nothing happens to Mick.
你这只歧恶的坏蛋到底在哪?
Now, where are you, you big ugly bugger?
它上勾了
This is as good as it gets.
来呀 到米克叔叔这里来
Come on. Come to Uncle Mick.
大
Big...
big...
大错特错
big mistake.
- 日安 米克 - 日安 杰科
- G'day, Mick. - G'day, Jacko.
你在干嘛?
What are you doing up there?
我嘛 只是在静坐思考 打算谋一份新行当
Just sittin' up here, thinking about a new career, mate.
你的船呢?
Where's your boat?
沉长眠湖底了
On the bottom.
- 怎么回事? - 鳄鱼把它拉下去了
- How'd that happen? - Croc pulled it under.
拉下去?
Pulled it under?
它有多大?
How big was it?
如你所见
That big.
现在我们咋办?
Now what?
让我们爬回岸边 然后执行第二项计划
Well, now we scramble ashore and go to plan "B. "
别动!
Don't move.
老弟 更糟的还在前头呢
Well, could be worse, mate.
不会吧? 那里怎么了 米克?
Oh, yeah? How's that, Mick?
别人可以看见我们在树上
Well, someone could see us up here,
比奸狡的鳄鱼更胜一筹
up the tree, outsmarted by a bloody crocodile.
愿主保佑 如果遇见蛇 我一定会立马倒毙的
So help me God, if I see a snake, I'm gonna drop dead.
他们不是捕鳄吗? 怎么捕到树上去了?
How are they gonna catch a crocodile up there in the tree?
嘿! 岸上的谁是第二捕鳄高手呀?
So, which one is the second best crocodile hunter in the land?
好了 各位 我们在此地的行程相当紧凑
Okay, everyone, we're on a tight schedule here.
我们接着走吧 不要打扰捕鳄勇士们了
We better keep moving. Don't want to disturb the hunters.
大家回到客车上去吧
Back on the bus, please, folks.
这边走
That's the way.
我们像对不折不扣的塘鹅 不是吗?
Bloody Nugget. Great, eh, mate?
你知道我讨厌鳄鱼什么吗? 它们像飞毛腿似的快!
Two best crocodile hunters in the entire Northern Territory, eh?
啊
Yeah.
我们看上去像一对鹈鹕 不是吗 嗯?
We look like a couple of real pelicans, don't we, eh?
你知道我为什么讨厌鳄鱼的吧 因为他们有腿 快走
You know what I hate about crocs? They got legs. Come on.
还记得从前用枪 躲杀它们的那些好时光吗?
Oh, remember the good old days when we just used to shoot 'em?
对啊老弟 不过"狡兔死 走狗烹"喔
Yeah, mate, but if there were no more crocs, they wouldn't need hunters.
没错 为了保持野猪的生态平衡 我们还是有用的
Oh, they'd need hunters... to keep the wild pigs in control.
野猪? 不 不能相提并论
Pigs? Oh, not the same.
我可不想被儿子耻笑: "这是我的爸爸 野猪邓迪"
I don't want my kid saying, "There goes my dad, Pig Dundee. "
难道你想被称作"肥猪杰科"?
Do you want to be known as Porker Jackson?
啊 绝不
Well, no.
呐 鳄鱼令我们与众不同 我们需要它
Nah, we need the crocs, mate. They make us somebodies.
没有了鳄鱼 我们仅仅是双腿布满齿印的老土冒罢了
Without 'em, we're just a couple of old bushwhackers with bite marks on our legs.
赶明儿还是这个时候来捉它吧
We'll get him tomorrow. Same time.
对了 我想起以前有个猪农的名字 就叫做"肥猪欧比安" 哈哈
Hey, I knew a pig farmer called Porker O'Brien once. Hah!
你知道为什么叫他"肥猪"?
You know why they called him Porker?
他又来这一套了
I hate it when he does that.
弄得我毛骨悚然
Gives me the creeps.
- 谢谢 - 不客气
- Thanks, mate. - No worries.
你刚刚从树上溜下来吧?
So, you got out of that tree all right, eh?
你怎么知道得这么清楚?
Now, how could you possibly know about that already?
我的族人常告诉我白人信得过 猪也会爬树了
My people have ways of talking that no white man can understand.
亚瑟 你真是个不折不扣的浑球
Arthur, you're so full of bullshit.
这也算是心灵感应吧?
No, it's a kind of mental telepathy, eh?
当然
Yeah, mental, all right.
啊 我刚刚发现一个和我们同宗的白人了
Ah, I think we just found out which one of us is the white man.
什么?
Yeah?
对 我听说了
Yeah, I heard about that.
对 他现在就在我身旁
Yeah, well, he's standin' right next to me now.
- 真是的 - 就这样 再联络
- Oh, great. - Yeah, okay. Yeah, later.
- 你今晚有表演吧? - 对
- So, are you doin' a show tonight? - Yeah.
日间表演已经完满结束了 继续令游客尽兴吧
Already did the matinee. Gotta keep the tourists happy, eh?
这个当然 最近以来他们 都是我们的衣食父母
Oh, well, mate, these days they're our bread and butter.
我们现在是20世纪 讲求发展旅游经济
That's sort of what we are now in the 20th century... tourist attractions.
如他们所说 这是縙乐产业
As they say, that's show business, mate.
米克 老实说
By the way, Mick,
现在已经是21世纪了
it's the 21 st century, mate.
我当然知道
Oh, yeah, I-I knew that.
- 再见 亚特 - 明天见
- See you, Art. - See you later.
- 再见 特洛依 - 再见 迈基
- See ya, Troy. - See ya, Mikey.
- 想去钓鱼吗? - 好呀
- Wanna go fishing? - Yeah.
- 今天学了些什么? - 还不是那些千篇一律的知识
- So, what did you learn today? - Oh, just school stuff.
不过我们今天看了地震的纪录片
But we had an earthquake video,
知道了美国的加州会发生地震
and we learned how they happen in California, America.
- 你在那的时候有遇到吗? - 不 我去的是纽约
- Did you see one when you were there? - No, I was in New York.
那儿可没有地震
They don't have earthquakes there.
如果有 那儿的人一定受不了 他们会像这样
People there wouldn't stand for it. They'd be like,
地震? 这可是布鲁克林
"Earthquake? Hey, this is Brooklyn.
滚出去 别管它了
Get outta here. Forget about it. "
他们真凶
They're tough.
现在是家庭作业时间 看那是什么?
Whoa, homework time. What's that?
- 鳄鱼粪 - 这说明它就是附近 找它去吧
- It's goanna turd. - That means he's close by. Find him.
- 他在那 - 是吗?
- There he is. - Yep.
- 你饿了? 要把它当晚饭吗? - 才不是呢
- You hungry? Want him for dinner? - Yuck, no way.
- 那你最好装作没看见 - 我绝不会袖手旁观的
- Then you better miss. - Dad, I never miss.
哇
Whoa.
爸! 快! 那儿有一只野猪 你能搞定它吗?
Quick, Dad, there's a big razorback up there. Can you do it?
- 干啥? - 你知道的 快使出绝招吧
- Do what? - You know, that trick. Please.
没问题 但如何它嗅到你有害怕的气息 那绝招就失灵了
All right, but it won't work if you're scared. He'll smell it.
我知道 我才不怕呢
I know. I won't be scared. I promise.
我叫你看你才看
Don't look at him till I do.
如果你有带刀的话我就无所畏惧了
I really won't be scared if I can carry your knife.
太棒了
Cool.
好的 爸 我会和米克商量的 嗯
Okay, Dad, I'll talk it over with Mick. Uh-huh.
不 如果我们决定要结婚的话
No. No, and if we decide we need to be married,
你会是第一个知道的人
I promise you'll be the first to know.
你要和小孙子说说话吗? 好的 请等等
Would you like to say hello to your grandson? Okay. Hang on.
迈基 和外公打个招呼吧
Hey, Mikey. Come say hi to Grandpa.
外公你好
Hi, Grandpa.
好得很
Pretty good, yeah.
怎么了?
So, what's new?
爸的报社在洛杉矶的分社 负责人汤姆 杰特兰德
Oh, Tom Zetland... he ran the L. A. bureau of Dad's paper...
刚在一宗交通意外中去世了
was just killed in a car accident.
- 他是你的朋友吗? - 老实说 不是
- What, was he a mate of yours? - Actually, no.
问题是 爸想我去顶他的位置
But the thing is, Mick, Dad is now pleading with me to take his place...
他希望我一直干下去
while he looks for a permanent replacement.
你说的你爸希望你去洛杉矶工作?
What you're sayin' is your dad wants you to go work for him in Los Angeles.
不错
Mm.
要去多久?
For how long?
这个嘛 我告诉他大概做几个星期吧
Well, I told him I might fill in for a few weeks.
老实告诉我 如何我也去的话
Well, tell me this, if we lived over there in the city,
- 那你就会去了? - 这个当然
- would you take the job then? - Oh, sure.
不是我自夸 我可是由报界大亨养大的
I mean, I was raised by a newspaperman,
或许天生就合适干这个呢
and, well, I don't know, I guess it just gets in your blood.
那就去吧 接受这份工作
That settles it then. Take the job.
至少到今年年底 我和迈基会和你一起去
At least for the rest of the year. Me and Mikey'll go with you.
- 你在开玩笑吧? - 不 这对迈基有好处 让他学会决策
- You're kidding? - No. Good for him. Help him decide.
决策?
Decide?
- 你爸是报业大亨吧? - 不错
- Your dad owns a newspaper, right? - Mm-hmm.
你是他的独女 总有一天迈基要继承家业的
You're his only child. Someday Mikey's gonna have to decide.
他是想做猎鳄勇士的助手呢...
Does he want to be an assistant crocodile wrangler...
还是大型报纸的掌舵人?
or the owner of a big-city newspaper?
这得好好想想这趟旅行对他非常有益
That's a tough one. And the travel will be good for him.
还记得那次令我眼界大开的纽约之旅吗?
Remember how my trip to New York sort of opened my eyes to the ways of the world?
让我变得...此话怎讲?
Made me a lot more... What's the word?
- 精于世故? - 就是这句
- Sophisticated? - Yeah.
米克 那这些猎鳄工具怎办?
By the way, Mick, what are you doing with that awful trap?
你不再用它们来对付那些可怜的动物了吗?
You're not going to use that on some poor animal?
我会把它们借给唐克
No, I'm lending it to Donk.
晚上常有小贼潜入他的酒吧...
Some mongrel's been sneaking into the pub at night...
敲碎他的酒坛
and knocking off his grog.
是的 偷他的酒
Stealing Donk's beer, well,
- 我想那些贼应有此报 - 是啊
- I guess they deserve to be mangled. - Yeah.
那你自己有什么打算 迈基? 你想怎样?
Well, what about you, Mikey? What do you think?
你想到加州去住上一段日子吗?
How would you like to live in California for a while?
- 那儿有地震 对吧? - 曾经有过
- They have earthquakes there, right? - Well, yeah, they have had.
太棒了!
Cool.
我就知道你会这样说 你一定会乐不思蜀的
I thought you might say that. You're gonna have lots of fun.
老实说 我担心的是你
Actually, you're the one I'm worried about.
不 我好得很
No, I'm fine.
米克 我还记得上次你从纽约回来后...
Um, Mick, I seem to remember after a few weeks in New York...
你变得相当坐立不安
you did get pretty antsy.
是有一点
Yeah, a bit antsy.
米克 我就爱你这样 你总是那么大公无私的
Mm, that's what I love about you, Mick. You're always so unselfish.
别担心
No worries.
比弗得山? 那可是明星住的地方
Beverly Hills, eh? Home to the movie stars.
大都在那
A lot of 'em, yep.
你不是电影从业员吧?
You're not in show business, are ya?
- 不 我是观光客 - 我也是
- No, I'm in the tourism game myself. - Hey, so am I.
每当我驾车的时候 我都这么 想实话说 我是个双栖工作者
When I'm out driving this. Actually, though, I'm a writer-actor.
在马车中间驾使豪华轿车 跟许多人打交道
Just, you know, drive the limo between gigs. Make a lot of connections.
我早上才接载过汤姆 阿诺德
Had Tom Arnold in the car this morning.
汤姆 阿诺德?
Tom Arnold?
我妻子大概会知道他是谁 她是报界的
Oh, wife probably knows who he is. She's- She's in the newspaper business.
- 记者 - 对
- A reporter. - Yeah.
你没见过他吧 看看这张照片
Here, take one of these. You never know.
谢谢
Thanks.
这个送你
There you go.
照得很漂亮
That- That's nice.
你可以收起它 我冲印了好多张
No, you can keep that. I got plenty of copies.
鳄鱼呀
Crocodile!
只征州税的减税计划
Okay, tax relief plan. State tax only.
这个没什么新闻价值 交通事故嘛...
No interest there. Traffic accidents.
洛杉矶司机和纽约司机的大比拼 这个不错
Okay, these figures comparing L. A. to New York drivers, that's good.
就按我说的去干
Follow through on that.
好的 我们的方针没变吧?
Great. So our policy hasn't changed then?
- 怎么了? - 就像杰特兰德先生所说的
- How so? - It's like Mr. Zetland used to say,
我们是一个纽约的报纸
"We're a New York paper.
除了纽约以外的新闻概不关心
If the news ain't about New York, then who gives a rat's ass? "
这话真是的
Or words to that effect.
他不太乐意在洛杉矶干吗?
So he wasn't too happy about working in L. A., huh?
不 汤姆爱在这干 他爱制作专题报道...
Oh, no, no. Tom loved it here. No, he loved doing expose features...
和调查冤假错案
and investigating scams and phonies.
- 他一直在跟进什么新闻? - 他在做一个这个专题...
- What was he working on? - He was doing this feature...
是关于一个新成立的迷你工作室
on this new mini studio.
他对这个极为感兴趣
He started to get really excited about it.
我想他可能嗅到了什么
I think he smelled a rat.
但实情如何 就只有汤姆才知道了
But what it was about, only Tom knew.
或许你可以找到他的兴奋点在哪 祝你好运
Maybe you can find out what sparked his interest in there. Good luck.
对了 你的家人在干嘛? 他们出去"探险"了吗?
Oh, hey, how are your boys doing? Are they out exploring?
是呀 他们一定会乐在其中的
Oh, yeah. Should be fun too. For both of them.
快来看呀!
Come on, people!
谢谢你们由衷的掌声 谢谢
Thank you. Oh, spontaneous applause, thank you.
谢谢
Thank you.
这次是从前后互抛
All right, a couple of tricks. Behind the back.
好 这次是从腿间穿插过去
All right, all right, all right, under the leg.
爸 那些女孩跟"海岸救险队"穿得一样
Hey, Dad, look. There's those girls from Baywatch.
- 什么? - "海岸救险队"
- What? - Baywatch.
电视剧呀 那里面的女孩都像这样...
On TV, you know? The girls that run funny, like this.
唐纳和酒吧里的男人都大叫"爽呀!"
And Donk and all the men in the pub go, "Whoa! "
- 你什么时候到酒吧去了? - 哇! 小心!
- What've you been doin' in the pub? - Whoa! Hey!
- 非常抱歉哇 肌肉型男 - 不要紧
- I am so sorry. Whew, muscle fatigue. - It's okay.
- 你没事吧? - 嘿 你知道现在几点了?
- You all right? - Hey, do you know what time it is?
大概是12点30分 35分也说不定
Oh, it's about 12:30, maybe 12:35.
真有意思 你明明戴着手表呀
Oh, that's cute, but you're wearing a watch.
- 这不是手表 是指南针 - 噢
- That's not a watch, it's a compass. - Oh!
我初到此地 离了它 可能连家门在哪都找不着了
Yeah, I'm new in town. I couldn't find my house without this.
真的? 那你家在哪?
Really? So where's your house from here?
离这11点5英理 东北减北2度
Eleven point five miles, two degrees north northeast.
一个叫比弗利山的地方
Called, uh, Beverly Hills.
比弗利山? 那你家一定很豪华吧?
Bev Hills? So, you have a nice home?
- 是的 对 我们有8间寝室 - 8个卫生间
- Yeah, we got eight dunneys. - Yeah, that's eight bathrooms.
- 真不错 这是你的小孩吗? - 是的 他叫迈基
- Oh, nice. This-This your boy? - Yeah, that's Mikey.
- 你已经结婚了? - 不 他还没
- So, you married? - No, he's not married.
- 那你看管小孩吗? - 是的 他是我儿子
- So you got custody? - Yeah. Well, Mikey's my son.
- 喔那你一定是个好父亲了 - 我敢说是的
- Right. So you're a good parent? - Well, I'd say.
太好了 上天终于给我梦想的牛仔了
Right. Oh, this is too good. I finally bump into a cute cowboy.
虽然他比布莱德彼特更具罗伯特 罗德福 的古旧气息 但也不错...
He's more Robert Redford's vintage than Brad Pitt's, but that's okay...
因为他有一栋在比弗得山的公寓 而且他还会看孩子
'cause he's got a mansion in Beverly Hills, plus he's got custody of his kid.
这表明他将会善待我的辛迪 此外...
That means he'd be a good dad to my Cindy and this is...
一定事有蹊跷 对不?
Oh, there's a catch, right?
怎么从天掉下这么大块舡酶呢?
Nothing this good ever happens to me.
你大概不喜欢女人的吧? 你是同性恋吧?
Are you... You're not available? You're- You're gay, right?
就大部分时间来说 都很开心
Um, most of the time, pretty happy, yeah.
当然
Of course.
有趣的牛仔 怀旧的气息 他一定是同性恋
Cute cowboy, Venice Beach, had to be gay.
我还是不要做梦了
What was I thinking?
- 她可真够唠叨的了 - 对 典型的美国女人
- Boy, she was a chatterbox. - Yeah, mate. American woman.
- 她臀部的曲线可真美 - 是呀
- She's got a nice ass. - Yeah. Hey,
你不能再去泡吧了
you gotta stop hangin' around that pub.
谁告诉你这些的? 纳格吗?
Who taught you that? Nugget?
- 发现什么可疑之处了吗? - 是的 听听这个
- Find anything fishy? - Yeah. Listen to this.
斯里沃基电影公司拍的 第一部电影是"致命毒物"吧?
Silvergate Pictures make their first movie, right? Lethal Agent.
这部电影真不怎么样
It's a total bomb.
然后他们又拍了"致命毒物2"...
So the very next picture they make is Lethal Agent II...
当然 这部也没多少人愿意租来看
which, of course, goes straight to video where no one rents it.
你猜他们用什么来挽回声誉?
And guess what they're doing now to save their reputation?
- 嗯... - 对了
- Uh... - Yeah.
我真不明白汤姆有采访过这帮人吗?
I don't know. Did Tom talk to these guys?
我想是的 他有高层到下属都采访过了
Yeah. I think he spoke to everybody from the president of the studio down.
他看来真的异常关注这宗消息
That's when he seemed to get really excited about the story.
我只看到这是愚蠢的商业交易
All I can see here is a bunch of really dumb business decisions.
当然 这是合法的
But, of course, that's not illegal.
据我对他的了解
Well, you know, that's the research I did for him.
汤姆的工作资料都在他的私人电脑里
Whatever Tom was working on is probably in his P. C.
如果你要看 我可以从他家拷贝出来
I can get the disk from his house, if you're interested.
那实在是太好了
That'd be great.
此外 我发现他们面向传媒 和工商界的欢迎招待会
And I notice they're having a "meet and greet" for press and industry people.
你知道这是谁印刷出版的?
Do you know who would normally cover that?
费伊 奥尔森公司策划的
Fay Olson does entertainment.
好的 请通知她我会出席宴会
Okay. Tell her she can have the night off, and I'll fill in.
- 爸 那是什么车呀 - 我现在不能左顾右盼
- Hey, Dad, what sort of car is that? - I can't look now, mate.
加州人平常温文尔雅的
These California people are nice and friendly and polite...
但当他们坐进驾驶座 便变得如狼似虎
till they get in their cars, then they turn into crazed wombats.
爸 快停车! 前面有条狗!
Quick, Dad, stop, there's a dog in the road.
哪呀?
Where?
- 狗在哪? - 他躲去那了
- So where's the dog? - He ducked in there.
我去抓它
I'll get him.
小心
Be careful.
诸位请退让一下 放心 我们会抓住它的
All right, everybody, stay back. Don't worry, we'll get him.
我来了
I'm on it.
- 他到底在干嘛? - 快开呀!
- What's the hell's goin' on up there? - Come on, buddy!
那个人说前方有东西
The guy said there's something on the road.
他在开玩笑吧?
He looks like a nut to me.
- 可能真有什么吧 - 那是什么?
- Probably a bomb or something. - It's a what?
- 他说是炸弹! - 炸弹! 随时会爆炸!
- He says it's a bomb! - It's a bomb! It's gonna blow!
出来! 小乖乖!
Come here, boy. Come on.
他害怕了 不敢出来
He won't come out. He's scared.
那不是狗 那是...
That's not a dog. That's a...
我也不太清楚 看是像负鼠一类的动物
I don't know what it is. Some kind of possum maybe.
我从没见到黑白相间的负鼠
I've never seen a black and white possum.
我想它是臭鼬吧
I think it's a skunk.
你怎么知道的? 我们又没养过臭鼬
How do you know what a skunk looks like? We don't have 'em at home.
它看上去像动画片里的皮休爷爷
It looks like Pepe Le Pew in the cartoons on TV.
我想臭鼬都是散发着恶臭的
I thought skunks were supposed to stink.
别放臭弹呀
Don't stink.
来呀 小乖乖 来呀
Come on, boy. Come on.
拆弹仪器准备好了 人质的位置也已确定
Possible explosive device and hostage situation.
好了 我们走吧
There we go.
很明显 它在害怕
No wonder he's scared.
那些该死的直升飞机
Those bloody helicopters.
起飞吧
Take off!
警察那儿好像遇到了棘手的事情
We have a very tricky situation for the police here.
好像是个小男孩被当成人质
The suspect appears to be holding a young boy hostage.
站住!
Stay where you are!
放下炸弹!
Put the bomb down!
怎么了?
What?
那不是炸弹 倒像只猫
That's not a bomb. That's a cat.
跟家乡一样 警察是我们的好朋友
Ah, see, just like at home. The policeman is your friend.
他们是来帮助我们的
They're here to help us.
那不是猫 是臭鼬
That's not a cat. That's a skunk.
- 把它从这带走吧 伙计 - 好的
- You can take it from here, guys. - Uh-uh.
迈基 我不会告诉你妈妈的
Uh, Mike, I wouldn't mention this to your mum.
她大概不会明白的 这是男人之间的秘密
She probably wouldn't understand. It's man stuff.
在今天下午的较早时间
Of course, at that stage, early this afternoon,
我们意想不到所谓的炸弹 竟然是一只臭鼬
we had no idea that the bomb was, in fact, a skunk.
警员极不情愿地将臭鼬放进警车里
Officers reluctantly placed the skunk in a squad car...
直至动物管理处有关人员前来接收
to await the arrival of animal control.
与此同时 造成了101国道上从加拉巴萨斯到...
In the meantime, it backed up traffic on the 101...
帕萨迪纳的史无前例的大堵车
from Calabasas to Pasadena, the worst traffic jam...
- 迈基 你在干嘛? - 亲爱的 是我
- What are you doing, Mikey? - Uh, it's okay, love, it's me.
是你呀 米克你今晚真的想参加吗?
Oh. Mick, are you sure you want to come tonight?
这是我不得不出席的社交应酬
I mean, it's a social thing, but it'll be work for me.
我热切期盼着
I'm lookin' forward to it.
可以藉此接触像纽约客那样友善的当地人
You know, to see if the local people are as friendly as New Yorkers.
希望儿子也有同感吧他 星期三就要去上学了
I hope your son feels the same way. He starts school on Wednesday.
放心好了 他和我一样 真的
Oh, no worries. He's, uh, he's just like me, really.
据我所知 他魅力过人 连臭鼬也不会喷他臭气
From what I hear, he has enough charm to stop a skunk from spraying him.
啊 是这样的: 我们当时正在高速公路上
Yeah, well, you know, we were roarin' down the freeway...
这没什么
It's okay.
- 你在电视上看来相当迷人 - 该死的电视
- You looked really cute on TV. - Bloody television.
不是现在
Not this time, pal.
- 米克! - 叫警察!
- Mick! - Call the cops!
让他走 他是帮我们停车的服务员
Let him go. He's the valet. He's supposed to park the car.
就是嘛 放松点 老哥
Yeah, yeah, take it easy, dude.
- 给他小费 - 抱歉
- Tip him. - Sorry.
- 无心之失 - 抱歉
- Honest mistake. - Sorry.
服务员?
Valet?
- 来一张? - 好的
- Picture, please. - Sure.
我们可以照一张吗?
Mind if we get a shot?
别担心 我只是来喝喝酒 凑和凑和
Don't worry. I'll just get a drink, blend right in.
好的 当我搞定那些繁文缛节 我就来找你
Okay. I'll come and get you after I've done the formalities.
来 对着镜头 笑得灿烂点
Big smile for the camera, please.
来 这是你的依云矿泉水
All right, that's your Evian, and this here's...
和开瓶器
your sparkling mineral water with a twist.
再来杯什么都不加的苏打水
Oh, and a straight club soda.
你是在喝酒呢还是在洗衣服?
So, you havin' a drink or doin' your laundry?
晚上好 我是米克 邓迪 请问你是...
G'day. Mick Dundee. And you're...
托尼 邓迪先生 您要喝点什么?
Tony. What can I get for you, Mr. Dundee?
来杯啤酒好了 劳驾
Just a cold beer'll do, mate. Thanks.
典型的洛杉机生活 一群呆瓜
That's typical of L. A. today. Health nuts.
操心一下他们的饮食
Worried about what they drink, worried about what they eat.
我也曾荒唐过 后来恍然大悟了
I used to be like that till I found the answer.
哦? 那你悟出了什么?
Oh? And, um, what's the answer?
咖啡尽情地吃 然后用咖啡来消毒
Coffee. Eat and drink whatever you please, then flush it out with coffee.
那你一定喝了不少咖啡
So you just drink lots of coffee.
不 喝的不是你 我是说大肠水疗法
No. You don't drink it. I'm talking colonics.
好的咖啡灌肠 使你通体畅快
A good coffee enema leaves you clean as a whistle.
喝光了
Bottoms up.
托尼 你知道灌肠剂...
Hey, Tony. An enema...
不是促进新陈代谢的吧
Isn't that where they shove a hose up the old...
- 不 很多人对此坚信无疑 - 用咖啡?
- Yep. Lots of people swear by 'em. - With coffee?
- 要加奶和糖吗? - 别傻了 这就是洛杉矶
- Cream and sugar? - It's L. A.
打扰一下 罗夫曼先生
Excuse me, Mr. Rothman.
我想向你介绍一个人
I'd love to introduce you to someone.
- 这位是"今日新闻报" 的苏查尔顿小姐 - 幸会
- Ms. Sue Charleton from Newsday. - Hello.
亚尔南 罗夫曼非常高兴认识你 迪第告诉你接掌了...
Arnan Rothman. Delighted. Didi tells me you've replaced...
我们的好朋友 汤姆 杰特兰德的位置
our late friend, Tom Zetland.
- 失陪一下 - 真是不幸 他人那么好
- Excuse me. - That's a shame. He was a good man,
他对公司的运作了如指掌
and he really knew his way around this business.
我恐怕自己的资历尚浅
Well, I'm afraid I come up a bit short in that department.
实话说 我衷心希望能得到你的帮助
Actually, I was hoping maybe you could help me out.
- 你在这无所事事? - 我? 不 我是来交际的
- Are you in the cast of this flick? - Me? Oh, no, I'm socializing.
扩展人际关系? 我也是你有看这几部电影吗?
Networking. Me too. Have you seen any of these masterpieces?
- 没呢 - 实话告诉你 它们劣得难以至信
- No. - Unbelievable schlock. I kid you not.
在电影界上简直难以立足
Makes you embarrassed to be in the business.
我看过比这更糟就是"致命毒物" 的第一和第二辑
The only thing I've seen worse than Lethal Agent was Lethal Agent II.
我看过些片断 糟透了
I read the script on this one, and it's even worse.
我简直不知道这帮蠢材 如何能在电影界混下去
I don't know how these clowns stay in business.
我想你应该听说过他们 正在拍"致命毒物4"吧?
I suppose you've heard, then, they're making Lethal Agent IV.
真的?
What?
没听说呀 他们已经在挑演员了?
No one told me. Do you know if they're casting yet?
我要通知我的经理人
I gotta call my agent.
我正计划接着汤姆的策划进行下去...
I'm planning on following through on Tom's story...
除了这部影片外 还要 更深入地了解你的电影公司
more about your film company than this particular film.
- 希腊的一切真叫人着迷 - 啊
- We shot the whole thing in Greece. - Oh!
这是我们的国际副总栽米洛斯 邓普尼克先生
Allow me to introduce Milos Drubnick, our international vice president.
- 这位是苏 查尔顿 - 非常高兴认识你 美国巨星
- Sue Charleton. - Delighted to meet American star.
我是你的忠实粉丝
I'm big fan, all your films.
非常感谢 很抱歉我是个记者
Well, that's very kind of you, but I'm a journalist.
- 苏是"今日新闻报"的 - 啊
- Sue's from Newsday. - Huh.
米洛斯掌管我们公司东欧方面的事务
Milos handles all our Eastern European activity.
他在那举足轻重
I could not work over there without him.
请原谅
You'll excuse me.
我就不在这多打扰你了
Well, I don't want to monopolize all your time here.
期待着与你在办公室的会面
I was hoping we could catch up at the studio.
我也期待着
Absolutely.
他们就喜欢这么干
That's just the way they do things.
亲爱的 别抽这个了
You don't want that, love.
随便吃点什么吧 会让你好受些的
Get some free food in you. You'll feel a lot better.
待会见
You're welcome.
- 你是从澳大利亚过来的吧? - 是的
- Hey, you're from down under, right? - Yeah.
你认识梅尔 吉布森吗?
I don't suppose you know Mel Gibson.
梅尔 吉布森? 认识 我两次从监狱里保释他出来
Mel Gibson? Ought to. Bailed him out of jail twice.
你瞎吹的吧? 你真的认识他吗?
You're kidding. You really do know him?
- 我可以告诉你他的一些逸事 - 洗耳恭听
- I could tell some tales about Mad Mel. - Please do.
你不是说已经和"今日新闻报" 的人毫无瓜葛了吗?
I thought you said we were finished with these prying Newsday people.
她只是按部就班罢了 我会处理的
She's just following up on the original story. I'll handle it.
不 她现在想打听制作室的 内部事宜你应该阻止她
No. Now she want to come snooping around studio. You should say no.
我们是电影界新丁 对吧?
Look, we're the new boys in town, right?
我们争取公众的认同
We're supposed to be begging for publicity.
如果禁止记者采访 我们就会和媒介搞僵了
We start banning the press, they're gonna be all over us.
这件事就交给我处理吧
Leave this to me.
- 他把鞋子脱掉 啊 谢谢 托尼 - 不客气
- He takes his shoes off... Thanks, Tony. - You're welcome.
赤足裸奔
Runs outside stark naked.
一把火烧光了整座楼房 他可真是个疯狂的混球
Sets fire to the building and burns it to the bloody ground.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
他说是米勒的好朋友但其实他们是亲兄弟
Mel Gibson's best friend. They're practically brothers.
我看过他们在一起
I've seen them together.
刚告诉他们一些米勒的逸事
Just tellin' 'em a few tales about Mel Gibson.
- 你并不认识梅尔 吉布森呀? - 不 我认识
- You don't know Mel Gibson. - Yeah, I do.
你也认识的 我们在唐纳的酒吧见过他
You know him too. Met him at Donk's pub.
就是那个红头发 走路一瘸一拐的家伙呀
Mel Gibson. Tall redheaded fellow, walks with a limp.
天 "马尔" 那是马尔科姆 吉布森 不是梅尔 吉布森
Oh, "Mal. " Malcolm Gibson. Not Mel Gibson.
对! 马尔 吉布森 想不到这儿也有人认识他!
Yeah, Mal Gibson. They know about him over here!
世界真小 不是吗?
Small world, isn't it?
嘿 米克有空给别忘了给我电话
Hey, Mick. Mick, you give me a call anytime.
没问题 找一天共进午餐吧?
Okay, dude. Hey! Maybe we'll do lunch.
- 米克 你还好吧? - 我喜欢好莱坞
- Mick, you're starting to scare me. - I like Hollywood.
午安 欢迎来到比弗利山
Good afternoon. Welcome to Beverly Hills.
谢谢
Thanks.
你关于电影工场的报道大受欢迎
So, your story on the film company just got red hot.
汤姆的住处被盗 他们偷光了所有财物
Tom Zetland's place was robbed, and they took everything.
天啊 这真可怕 但为什么会使报道受到热捧?
Oh, my God, that's terrible. But how does it make the story hot?
大概是汤姆的意外遇害吧
Tom is accidentally killed?
他的家被洗劫一空 什么线索都没留下?
His place is cleaned out, leaving no clues to what he's working on?
也许汤姆掌握了某些重大秘密
Maybe Tom was on to something big,
他们想杀人灭口
and they had to shut him up.
你认为是他是被电影公司的人谋杀了?
You think the film people had him killed?
也不是不可能的
It's possible.
一开始我就有不祥的预感
I had a bad vibe about this from the start.
我认为你到电影公司要小心行事
I think you should be careful going out there.
我不打算深入虎穴
Well, I'm not exactly going into a Mafia stronghold.
我去采访制作室的负责人就够了
I'm interviewing a studio head on the lot.
我还带了家人来 他们是来观光的
I'm even bringing my family along. They're gonna do the tour.
欢迎诸位大驾光临
Well, all righty, then. Welcome, ladies and gentlemen, boy and girls,
欢迎参加派拉蒙电影公司的影画之旅
to the Paramount Pictures tour.
神奇之旅就要开始了在此之前...
This is where the magic happens, people. But before we actually begin,
我想请诸位举起右手
I'm gonna ask you all to raise your right hand.
很好现在请你们见证...
Okay, cool. Now what you're about to witness...
电影制作的最神秘之处
are some of the biggest secrets of movie-making.
因此你们必须宣誓保密
So I must ask that all of you swear not to reveal anything you witness here.
你们敢起誓吗?
Do you swear?
说"我愿意"就行了
Uh, just say, "I do."
- 我愿意 - 非常好
- I do. - Okay.
这帮右撇子
Righty-o, Jim.
今天在座诸位将会受到特殊礼遇
Oh, wow, you're in for a special treat here today, people,
因为我们正在参与真实的拍摄过程为斯里沃电影工场的"致命毒物3"
'cause just up ahead we're actually filming a giant crowd scene for the latest...
而特地制作的巨型布景
Silvergate Studio picture, Lethal Agent III.
我早跟你说应该去参观环球电影公司
I told you we should've gone to Universal.
由于第一第二部电影的成本太低
Because quite simply, losses on the first two movies...
原因很简单 前两部电影的亏损...
are amortized into the cost of the franchise.
必须计算在特许经营商的成本里 事实上 我们分文不赚
We're making this movie for practically nothing.
不过 你们有想过降低电影的成本吗?
Okay, but still, wouldn't it be cheaper to make your films...
取消两处经营 只选择在这里或者是在东欧?
either here or in Eastern Europe instead of both places?
当然 不过我们的电影都是在东欧拍的
Sure, but our movies are set in Eastern Europe.
你不可以在此地模拟制作场景吗?
You can't fake the locations here?
你看 他们正在隔壁拍摄非洲丛林的场景
I mean, they're shooting an African jungle next door.
苏 我们可以私底下谈谈吗?
Sue, can you and I talk off the record?
- 可以请你稍稍避让一下吗? - 好的
- Will you excuse us for a minute? - Sure.
开门见山地说吧
Quite frankly, the, uh,
一部电影的成与败
the success or failure of these films...
对我们而言毫不重要
is of little importance to us.
我们在放长线钓大鱼
We're after bigger fish.
在苏联的...
There are over 300 million people...
三亿观众
in what was once the Soviet bloc.
他们在迫切渴望着縙乐表演
People who are starved of entertainment.
电影就在他们那里取景 本国人担当主角
Movies shot in their own backyard, starring their own people.
我说的是建立起大型的工作坊和连锁院线
I'm talking about building major studios, cineplex chains,
甚至是主题公园
even theme parks.
我想说的重点是将建立在欧洲的迷你迪士尼
The deal I am talking about will make Euro Disney seem penny-ante.
啊 这是一宗振奋人心的消息俄国的好莱坞
Well, this is a great story. A Russian Hollywood.
我们什么时候才可以报道这宗新闻?
And when do we go on record?
两个星期后的头条如何?
Two weeks, tops.
但对你来说
But for you,
将会是你掌管"今日新闻报"的
24 hours before the rest of the world.
最后24小时
Exclusive to Newsday.
那以什么作为报答?
And in return?
推迟你已经开始的连载那篇什么来着?
Postpone the piece you've already started. Right now, what is it?
一篇关于小规模工作室...
It's a... It's a story about a small-time studio...
以及两部失败的电影作品的报道
and their two unsuccessful movies.
谁会在意呀
Who cares?
你意下如何?
What do you say?
好吧
Well,
作为"今日新闻报"的负责人 我想你成交了一宗以买卖
if it's a Newsday exclusive, I guess you got a deal.
克莱尔 带查尔顿小姐 去参观一下电影场景吧
Claire, why don't you take Ms. Charleton down to the set.
你将会盾到生意场上富于魅力的一面
You can see the glamorous side of the business.
随时联系我
I'll be in touch.
干得好
You are good.
这里是普通凡人...
...where we can transform an ordinary man orwoman...
摇身一变为伦人或小丑的地方
into an ape or a clown.
接下来 在我们要进入下个景区前
All righty, then. Now, before we enter this next portal,
我郑重提醒你们丛林 中有很多危险的动物...
it is my duty to warn you that several dangerous jungle creatures...
在随处游荡 所以请不要离开电车
have been sighted on the loose, so keep inside the tram at all times.
我可不想再多失去一个人了
I don't want to lose anyone... again.
- 爸 你有带大刀吗? - 没想过我会在这用得着它
- Dad, do you have your big knife? - Didn't think I'd need it here.
我只随身带了小刀 你要来干嘛?
I might have my pocket knife. What do you need it for?
- 以防有有野兽出没 - 我想没有事的
- In case the jungle animals attack. - I think we'll be all right.
诸位请小心! 有一条巨大蟒蛇!
Okay, look out, folks, it's a giant deadly anaconda!
- 伙计 这太可怕了 - 抱歉 这是条件反射
- Well, that's awesome, dude. - Sorry, reflex action.
没有 你太厉害了
Okay. Cool.
我们离开这吧
Let's get outta here.
嘿 这是表演吗?
Hey, is he part of the show, or what?
你好
G'day.
- 这也是男人之间的秘密吧 爸爸? - 你说对了 伙计
- Was that more man stuff, Dad? - You got that right, mate.
- 你们好 玩得开心吗? - 太棒了
- Hey, you two. Did you have fun? - Yeah, it was cool.
对 你的访问进行得如何?
Yeah. So how'd your interview go?
感觉不太好
Creepy.
你曾经和一个谎言连篇的人交谈吗?
Did you ever talk to someone and think everything they're saying is a lie?
有呀 就是纳基
Yeah. Nugget.
纳基个无关痛痒的家伙 但这个人...
Well, Nugget's harmless. This guy...
你知道什么是该做的吧? 你的报纸跟警察关系不错吧?
You know what you should do? Your paper's got police connections, right?
你让警察暗中调查他吧
You get the cops to do a background check on him.
纽约重案组就是这么干的
That's the way they do it on NYPD Blue.
嗯 看来迈基不是唯一...
Hmm. Well, I see Mikey's not the only one glued...
沉迷于电视剧的人
to the TV all day long.
我们只是看教育节目 对吧 小家伙?
But we only watch educational programs. Right, mate?
对 像摔角一类的节目
Yeah. Like wrestling.
你嗅到到岩石的愤怒气息了吗?
"Can you smell what the Rock is cooking? "
- 他今天有乖乖的吗? - 他乖像小狗一样
- Well, did he behave today? - Yeah, he was good as gold.
我不是问你 我是在问迈基
I wasn't talking to you. I was talking to Mikey.
喔
Oh.
不许再看电视了 你明天就要上学了
And no more TV. You start school tomorrow.
早安 我是米克 邓迪
G'day. Mick Dundee.
我的小不点第一天上学 我是来接他的
Here to pick up my ankle biter. It's his first day.
我是巴利 卡兹 你儿子上几年级了?
Ah, Barry Katz. What, uh, grade's he in?
- 四年级 - 我儿子也是
- Uh, fourth. - Oh, same as my boy.
我儿子在三年级 我是艾里克 贝利
My boy's in the third. Eric Berry.
- 你好 艾里克 - 你看去像个喜爱野外探险的人
- Hi, Eric. - Well, you look like an outdoors man.
你觉得幸存者这个活动怎么样?
What do you think of this whole survival camp idea?
那是什么玩意?
What is it?
是学校将举办的为了 训练如何在野外生存的夏令营
The school's puttin' it on this summer. Teach kids how to survive in the woods.
包括钓鱼和起营 也欢迎父亲一起去
Fishing, making campfires. Dads are welcome.
- 噢 - 我觉得这主意不错
- Oh. - I think it's a great idea.
让他们有机会亲近大自然 我打算让格兰自个去
Gives them a chance to get in touch with nature. I'm gonna take Gary along.
对你来说也挺好 可以和你的孩子一起
Good for you. Couple of weeks in the bush,
在丛林中呆几个星期 你们会乐在其中的
you and your boy, you'll both love it.
你常带孩子到里外去吧 你们从哪来的 澳洲吗?
You ever take your boy into the outback where you were? Down under?
经常去
All the time.
我上个月才带他到丛林里玩
Just last month, I took him into the bush.
教他如何用树枝猎杀野猪
Taught him how to kill a wild boar with a stick.
杀野猪? 但他只有九岁!
Kill a boar? But he's, like, nine years old!
俗语有云: "迟做比不做好"
Yeah, well, you know what they say. Better late than never, eh?
呆会见
Ah. See you later, fellas.
爸 玛蒂斯小姐有话要跟你说 我在那边等你
Hey, Dad. Ms. Mathis wants to talk to you. I'll meet you over there.
- 我是桃乐茜 玛蒂斯 查尔顿先生 你好 - 你好吗?
- Dorothy Mathis, Mr. Charleton. - Oh, how do you do?
其实我是米克 邓迪 还是迈基的父亲
Actually, it's Mick Dundee. But I'm Mikey's dad.
啊 是的 邓迪先生
Oh, Mr. Dundee. Right.
首先 迈基是一个 可爱 聪明 友善的好小孩
Well, first off, Mikey is a lovely boy. Bright, friendly.
只是有个小小的问题 他到哪都是用跑的
There's just one small problem, one we run into all the time here.
我们称之为"好莱坞综合症"
We call it the "Hollywood Syndrome."
就像电影中爸爸是警官的小孩一样
Like when a dad plays a policeman in a movie,
他们常常会以假当真
the children often believe he's actually a policeman.
对了 你的学生当中不少是演员的孩子
Oh, right, you've got a lot of actors' kids here.
我不是演员 只是观光客 没那么玄乎
I'm not in the movie business, I'm in the tourism business. Not so glamorous.
老实说 你儿子常常把生活想像得
Exactly. Which is why your son tries to make it...
过分的丰富多彩
sound a bit more colorful than it really is.
当然 这好像无伤大雅 但必须防微杜渐
Now, it seems harmless, but little fibs can grow.
他说什么了?
What's he been sayin'?
非常遗憾地告诉您 他到处宣扬您是个猎人
I'm afraid he told everyone you're a hunter,
还说你猎杀了不少鳄鱼
and you hunt and kill crocodiles.
他说得不全对
Oh. He knows better than that.
鳄鱼是受保护动物 我只是活捉它们
Crocodiles are protected. I don't kill 'em. I catch 'em alive.
是吗? 哦 当然是的
Oh? Well, yes, of course.
我会跟他谈谈 让他学会诚实
I'll talk to him. There'll be no more fibs.
桃乐茜小姐 认识你相当高兴
Really nice to meet you, Dorothy.
真像个猎人
Looks like a hunter.
挺帅的
Nice butt.
爸 你有跟老师说我姓邓迪 而不是查尔顿吗?
Dad, will you tell the teachers to call me Dundee, not Charleton?
我们是以你妈妈的姓登记入学的
Oh, sure. We just had to enroll you at school under your mother's name...
因为那你在这的名字
'cause that's your legal name over here.
是因为你没有和妈妈结婚的缘故吗?
Is that 'cause you won't marry Mum?
不 我们可以说是结婚了
Oh, no, we're married... sorta.
只是没去登记罢了
We just haven't done the legal bit yet.
当小朋友们知道爸爸是猎鳄好手 他有什么反应?
So what'd the kids say when you told them your dad was a crocodile hunter?
他们说: "那他在比弗山干什么?"
They said, "Well, what's he doing in Beverly Hills? "
聪明的孩子们
Smart kids.
爸 那个男的在干嘛?
Hey, Dad, what's that man doing?
我也不清楚 去问问他的
I don't know. Let's go and ask him.
打扰了 先生你在干什么?
Excuse me, mister. What are you doing?
我在静坐冥想 小伙子
Well, I'm meditating, young man.
什么是静坐冥想?
What's meditating?
就是我的灵魂不受外界干扰地优游在别处
Meditating is a special place I go in my mind where there's no distraction,
同时接收体内涌泉而出的力量
and I receive a great source of power.
太棒了! 你能为我们表演一下吗?
Cool. Can you show us how, please?
当然可以 来坐在我的对面吧
Sure. Come forward and have a seat.
- 我是迈基 请问你是? - 迈基你好 我是迈克
- My name's Mikey. What's yours? - Hi, Mikey. I'm Mike.
你好 我是米克 迈基的父亲
Oh, hi, Mike. I'm Mick, Mikey's dad.
迈基 米克 迈克 你们是在拿我开心吧?
Mikey, Mick, Mike. You gotta be kidding me, right?
- 绝对不是 - 好吧 盘起你的腿
- No. - Okay, okay. Hold your legs...
像个佛教徒那样
like in a Buddha position,
双手抓住脚踝 忘却不安
grab your ankles to save yourself some discomfort,
这是很容易的—闭上眼睛 放松
and, um, we're gonna take it easy... close your eyes, relax.
深深地吸一口气
Inhale the positivity,
慢慢呼出来
exhale the negativity.
深深地呼气
Inhale the positivity,
缓缓地呼气
exhale the negativity.
慢慢睁开眼睛 唤醒自我 放松
Open your eyes. Wake up. Relax.
- 感觉怎样? - 充满了能量
- How do you feel? - Very powerful.
这就对了 大地的力量 是力量之源
And that's the ticket, daddy-o... power. It's all in the power.
迈基 你能离开一会吗? 我想和迈克谈会话
Mikey, would you just hurry up ahead. I need to talk to Mike for a minute.
- 好的 - 是私人秘密
- Okay. - In private.
- 谢谢你 迈克再会 再见 - 迈基 路上小心
- Thanks, Mike. See ya. - You're welcome, Mikey. Take care.
迈克 我需要帮忙
Now, Mike, I need a favor.
你知道吗? 每个人都需要我的帮忙
You know, Mick, everybody needs a favor from me.
我的关节僵了 你可以拉我一把吗?
Well, I need you to help me up. My knees have locked.
那是我的老毛病 就你知道
That's my bad right there. You got it, buddy.
我可不想让儿子看见我这么不中用噢 行了!
I didn't want my kid to see. Oh! There.
谢谢
Thank you.
爸 你看到迈克的肌肉了吗? 它们块头多么大!
Hey, Dad, did you see the size of Mike's muscles? They were huge.
不错 但凡事不能只看表面
Yeah. You see, you should never judge a book by its cover.
迈克 大块头 像是砖块搭起来的
That Mike... big man, built like a brick dunney,
但我很中肯地说 他确实是个绅士
but I could tell straightaway he was a gentle man.
他连一只苍蝇都不忍伤害 这是一种天赋
He wouldn't hurt a fly. I just know people. It's a gift.
请你们把划分这些地方
I need you guys to tear this place apart.
这有个保龄球 和纯海洛因
Ah, it's the bowlin' ball. Pure heroin.
- 它大概藏在某处 - 仔细查看保龄球吧
- I know it's here somewhere. - Check out the bowlin' ball.
- 这些保龄球内有乾坤? - 我敢肯定有
- Hey, what about this bowling ball? - There, I knew it.
- 苏! - 怎么了?
- Hey, Sue! - Hmm?
- 亲爱的 你在干嘛? - 尝试重新从记者角度看问题
- What are you doin', love? - Trying to think like a journalist again.
我曾经精于此道
I used to be pretty good at it.
虽然从来没有人会把...
Not that anyone was gonna put...
苏 查尔顿和约瑟夫 普利策相提并论
Sue Charleton and Pulitzer Prize in the same sentence,
不过...我碰到难题了
but, ah, I'm just stumped.
就是关于那个工作室的事吗?
Is it that, uh, film studio thing?
我敢肯定主办人一定有阴谋 但到底是什么呢?
I'm sure it's an elaborate front for something. But what?
他们在走私
They're smugglin'.
- 毒品或者枪支 - 你怎么会这样推断?
- Drugs or guns. - How do you arrive at that?
通常都是这样的
That's what it always is.
走私到美国最值值钱的东西就是毒品
The big money thing they smuggle into America are drugs.
而最大的走私品就是 枪支
And the big thing goin' out... guns.
这样呀
Oh.
你这种对犯罪活动的洞察力是哪来的?
And where did this insight into major criminal activities come from?
从电视上学来的 我学得很快
Oh, from TV. I'm a quick learner.
我看起来像个土冒 但内心精明得很呢
I look like I just fell off the turnip truck, but I didn't land on my head.
你知道你急需什么? 一个间谍
You know what you need? You need a mole.
- 间谍? - 对 就是我 我将那工作室谋份工作
- A mole? - Me. I'll get a job at the studio.
米克 我知道闲得发慌 但是
Oh, Mick, I know you need something to do, but...
我在那个宴会上认识了不少人
I made a lot of contacts at that movie party.
我想其中一个能介绍我到那去
I bet one of them could get me a job there.
那迈基呢? 早上谁送他去上学?
Well, what about Mikey? Who's gonna take him to school in the morning?
这至关重要 你就放心让我去做吧
No worry. Leave it to me. This is important.
我有时想小迈基大概也觉得我是乡巴佬
See, sometimes I think young Mikey thinks I'm a bit of a hillbilly.
当然 我确实是个乡巴佬
Well, I am, actually.
我想让他知道乡巴佬并不意味着一无是处
I wanna show him that being a hillbilly doesn't necessarily mean you're dumb.
第一分队 在大街上闲逛
So our first group, stroll up the street,
以轻快的步子跟在三位商人
followed by our three businessmen at a more brisk pace...
和两名建筑工人的身后
and then our two construction workers!
- 迪亚哥 罗萨勒斯 - 幸会 我是米克 米克 史密夫
- Diego Rosales. - Yeah, Mick. Mick Smith.
很高兴认识你 米克
Nice to meet you, Mick.
我们正身处柏林 因此要像德国人那样走路!
Now, we're in Berlin, so please walk like Germans!
德国人怎么走路的?
How do Germans walk?
- 一脚前一脚后? - 是这样
- One foot after the other? - Okay.
现在再排一遍! 只要群众演员就行了!
So, this is a rehearsal! Background only!
开拍!
And... action!
你们到底在干什么?
What the hell are you doing?
我打算让儿子能在电影里见到我
I just wanted my kid to see me in the picture.
打开始你就忘着镜头转动就行了
Yeah, well, if you start looking at the camera during the take,
- 他们会把有你的镜头剪掉的 - 是呀
- they'll take you out of the picture. - Oh.
- 你是新来的吧? - 对 第一次有些紧张
- You're new, aren't you? - Yeah, first role. Bit nervous.
停! 回到原位
Cut! Back to one, please!
- 别紧张 像我这样 - 好的
- Just relax. Watch me, okay? - Yeah.
忘掉镜头吧
Forget about the camera.
我们两个工人正在去酒吧的路上
We're two working stiffs on our way to a bar.
- 把它当作日常生活就行了? - 没错
- Oh, just pretend it's real life? - Yeah.
注意! 我们这次来真的了! 要记住...
Okay, now, people, we will be doing it for real this time, and remember...
注意!
attention, please!
- 安静! 开始拍了! - 安静!
- Quiet, everyone! Picture's up! - Quiet!
- 开始! - 声音效果!
- Roll! - Sound speed.
场记!
Marker.
好 群众演员开始!
Set. And... background action.
开始!
And action.
抓住他!
Stop that man!
- 停! 停! - 伙计 你没事吧?
- Cut! Cut! - Man, are you okay?
- 到底怎么一回事? - 是我错 我一看见他跑来...
- What the hell happened? - It was my fault. I saw him runnin'...
是这样的 我试着去扶他 谁知他一头栽倒了
Uh, what happened is that he... he tried to catch him as he fell.
我们看着他失足 他摔得挺重的 你没事吧?
We saw him trip. He went down hard. Are you sure you're okay?
- 还好你只是试试 伙计 - 我们重新来吧
- Thanks for trying, buddy. - Okay, we'll go again.
各就各位! 快! 天快要暗下来了
Back to one! Fast as you can! We're losing the light!
谢谢你替我掩饰
Hey, thanks for covering up for me.
我就是控制不了 就像橄榄球回传似的条件反射
I couldn't help it, you know? Reflex. Sort of like a football flashback.
橄榄球? 我的天 那可是违规的擒摔
Football, my ass. That wasn't exactly a legal tackle.
在我们家乡叫做木钉挂衣架 不管怎么说 我欠人个人情
It is at home. It's called a dowel and coat hanger. Anyway, I owe you one.
不 不必客气 这必须留你在这
No, no, it's okay. I had to keep you here.
你真有趣 我要看看你在 下一场拍摄里怎样搅局
You're fun. I want to see what you're gonna do to screw up the next take.
走着瞧吧
Okay.
怎么了 迈克尔?
Oh, uh, what's the problem, Michael?
老师 美国人喜欢养老鼠呢? 还是说老鼠只是害虫?
Miss, do people like rats in America, or are they just pests?
- 你为什么会这么问? - 书架里有只大老鼠
- Why do you ask? - There's a big rat in the bookshelves.
- 它死了吗? - 还没呢 老师
- Is it dead? - No, Miss.
我只是把它打昏了爸说 除非要吃掉 否则不要
I only stunned it. Dad says never kill anything unless you're gonna eat it.
呃
Eww!
请你把它扔出去吧
I think we'll just put it outside, please.
他是我最好的朋友
He's my best friend, you know?
在这混得开的关键就是 别让你的脸在镜头出现
The key to survival here is you gotta keep your face away from the camera.
那他们就可以多次使唤你了
That way they can use you again and again.
- 几乎每个群众镜头都有我在 - 你可真是专家
- I've been in every mob scene. - You're a pro.
诸位安静!
All right, everyone! Settle down!
- 停住! - 重来!
- Settling! - Try again.
群众演员开动!
And background action!
开动!
Action.
看这边! 看这边! 奇奇 来一杯!
Watch this! Watch this! Kiki, get me a drink.
停! 不是这样的!
Cut! This isn't working.
这只猴子怎么了?
What's the problem with the monkey?
抱歉 它刚刚还好好的 奇奇 来这
Sorry. She was fine earlier. Come here, Kiki. Come here.
来这边!
Come here.
不知怎么回事 它从不会这样的
I don't understand. She never does this.
来这边 奇奇!
Come here, Kiki!
它只是有点紧张 你想让它干什么?
She's just a bit nervous. What do you want her to do?
- 你从事过和动物有关的工作吗? - 是的
- You ever work with animals? - Yeah.
- 可以这么说 - 它本来是要到桌上去...
- Kinda. - She's supposed to go to the table...
拿一瓶苏打水给男主角
and take a soda to the actor.
- 健糖的还是一般的? - 随便 健糖的吧
- Diet or regular? - Whatever. Diet.
- 要拿杯子盛着吗? - 它没学过这个
- Want a glass? - She hasn't learned that.
要拿杯子盛着吗? 它没学过这个
We're running late here.
多来一次吧? 如果还是不行 那就算了
Can we try one more time? If this doesn't work, we'll drop it.
好吧 各归各位这次是实拍了
Okay, back to one. This is the real thing, everybody.
集中精神! 开动!
Concentrating. Roll!
- 摄像机开动! - 灯光! 场记!
- Picture's up! - Speed. Marker.
- 群众演员开动! - 开动!
- And background action! - Action!
快来看呀! 快来看呀!
Watch this. Watch this!
奇奇! 给我来一杯!
Kiki, get me a drink.
要健糖的
Make it a diet one.
和一个玻璃杯! 谢谢 我的战友!
And a glass too! Thank you, mein Liebchen.
停! 冲印胶卷! 检查一下门!
Cut! Print! Check the gate.
噢!
Whoo!
留住他
Book him.
我碰到了麻烦 丛林景区里全是我饲养的动物
Look, uh, I got a problem. All my animals are on the jungle set,
我不能整天照看着这只黑猩猩
and I can't keep coming back and forth with the chimp.
如果你替我饲养它 我给你双倍人工
So if you'll fill in for me, I'll double what you're getting paid.
我还是属于这家公司的吧?
Will I still be on this picture?
每天都是 奇奇是我们的首席演员
Every day. Kiki's an above-the-title player.
我答应了
You got a deal.
你是个驭猴者了
You're looking at the new monkey wrangler.
- 谢谢你的帮忙 迪亚哥 祝好运 - 米克!
- Thanks for your help, Diego. - Dude, Mick!
这个是你职业生涯的转折点
Hey, hey, this is a positive career move.
- 当真? - 我跟你说 你可是迈出一大步了
- Reckon? - I'm telling you, you're gonna go far.
不过 别表现得太奇怪了
Ah! Don't be a stranger now.
真是个好人
Hell of a nice guy.
迈基!
Mikey!
等我一下
Wait just a minute, dear.
- 再见 迈克 - 再见 迈基
- See ya, Mike. - Bye, Mikey.
我还以为你父亲还会还接你呢
I suppose your father's picking you up again.
他这周有工作在身
Nah, he's at work this week.
噢 真糟 那你怎么回家?
Oh. Bummer. Well, how are you getting home then?
像其他小朋友一样
I've got a nanny like all the other kids.
谁来接你?
Oh! Which one's yours?
那儿 那个大块头
Over there. The big one.
- 你的保姆吗? - 不 是从家乡来的杰科叔叔
- Your nanny? - He's Uncle Jacko from back home.
- 他结婚了? - 还在寻觅中
- And is Uncle Jacko married? - No, but he's looking.
你好 我是迈基的老师 桃乐茜 玛蒂斯
Hi. Dorothy Mathis. I'm Mikey's teacher.
你好 桃乐茜请叫我杰科
G'day, Dorothy. Call me Jacko.
妙呀妙
Bloody marvelous.
这就是洛杉矶?
Los Angeles, eh?
多么有意思的名字
Funny name.
洛杉矶
Los Angeles.
你说对了 "迷失天使"
Yeah, it means, uh, "lost angels."
那是意大利语吧 就是那儿
It's Italian. Ah, there it is.
我跟苏说好了 要带你去一顿别具一格的晚饭
I told Sue I'd take you somewhere really special for dinner.
相信我 你会一见钟情的
You're gonna love this place. Trust me.
来 点你爱吃的吧
Now, pick out what you want of the menu here...
然后对着那个盒子大声说出来
and you yell it out into that box.
两分钟后 你不必离开车厢...
Two minutes later, you're scarfing it down...
就可以拿到它们了
without even getting out of the car.
城里人都在免下车餐馆带餐回家
We have these drive-ins back home in the cities,
这儿提供一条龙服务
but this is where it all started.
狼吞虎咽也没人管你
So you can eat like a pig and no one can see you.
精明的家伙 不是吗?
Clever buggers, these Yanks, eh?
大概就是洛杉机矶凭它的餐饮
Well, this is why L. A. is famous all around the world...
美名远扬的缘故吧
for its fine cuisine.
欢迎光顾温迪餐馆 请问要点什么?
Welcome to Wendy's. Can I take your order?
让我来 晚上好 温迪
Let me handle this. Good evening, Wendy.
车上将会有4个人
There will be four of us dining in the car this evening.
我们要4个三层芝士汉堡...
So we're gonna need four triple burgers with cheese...
四盒大薯条
and four Biggie Fries.
4个传统汉堡...
So that's four Classic riples...
- 等等 - 四盒大薯条?
- Uh, wait a minute. - and four Biggie Fries?
斯坦和享利也在车上
Uh, here comes Stan and Harry.
他们将和我们共进晚餐
Uh, they'll also be dining with us tonight,
因此我们要6个三层芝士堡...
so we need... six triple burgers with cheese...
和6盒大薯条
and six Biggie Fries.
好的 6个传统汉堡和6盒大薯条
Okay. Six Classic ripples with cheese and six Biggie Fries?
- 你知道我最想干嘛? - 啥呢?
- You know what I'd really like to do? - What's that?
爬到其中一座摩天大楼的顶上
Go right up on the roof on one of those skyscrapers.
那太容易了 你只要找开门的就行了
That's easy. Just find one that's open.
这儿确实比艾尔斯岩要高得多
S'truth. This is higher than Ayers Rock.
不过 纽约的摩天大厦比这还要高
Yeah. Of course, the buildings in New York are a lot higher.
我去过那儿
I was there, you know.
古旧的纽约
Old New York.
或者叫它做"大苹果"
Or as we call it, the "Big Apple."
"大苹果"? 为什么这么说?
Big Apple? Why do you call it that?
原因嘛...是因为它幅原辽阔...
Well, because it's really big and, uh...
而且建筑都要比这的安全
Yeah, but none of those buildings are as dangerous as this.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
因为纽约无地震
Well, they don't have earthquakes in New York.
但在这时常发生 不是吗?
They have 'em here all the time, right?
不错
Yeah.
我们现在就碰上了
We could have one right now.
天呀
God!
你猜这座大楼会怎么样?
What do you reckon it'd do to this building?
在它摇晃以前 我是怎么也不会动的了
Hey, I wouldn't wanna be up here if she started shakin', eh?
我看够了 你呢?
I've seen enough. You done?
我也看够了 不值一提的景色
Oh, yeah. No point in hangin' round.
这种摇晃没事吧?
This quake-safe?
没事的
No worries.
伙计 在下了1286层台阶后 我要喝一杯
Oh, mate, I need a drink after all those 1, 286 stairs.
放松 伙计
No worries, mate.
好像作用不大
Didn't work.
看来我们得等等 数以百计的车在通得...
Well, you gotta wait. There's hundreds of cars going through...
但只有我们俩想过马路
and just us two trying to cross.
是吗? 那现在有20个我们了对吧?
Yeah? Now there's 20 of us, eh?
你不能这么干 这是违法的
Yeah, but you can't do that. It's illegal.
我没看到有警察
Well, I don't see any cops.
交叉路口有摄像机的
Yeah, but they have cameras at all these intersections, see?
如果你行差踏 就会自动照下来 然后罚款
If you do anything wrong, they take your picture and send you a fine.
不过 我后背没有数字呀
Yeah, but I ain't wearing a number plate around my neck,
他们怎么认得出是我?
so how the hell are they gonna know who I am, huh?
当你入境时 要出示护照的 是吧?
When you landed here, you showed 'em your passport, right?
- 是呀 - 那就有你的照片了
- Yeah. - Got your picture in it, dopey.
有道理
Oh, yeah, right.
我想知道他们会怎么罚款
I wonder how much they fine you.
那就要看你按了多少次按钮了
It all depends on how many times you push the button.
- 那跟我们真像 - 德克萨斯酒吧 我们进去
- This looks like us. - Great. Texas bar. We're in.
一定很多乐子可寻
This could be a bit of fun.
美国的牛仔都喜欢喧闹的酒吧
These American cowboys like a good barroom brawl.
晚上好 请进
Howdy, boys. Step on in.
晚上好 小姐
Howdy, ma'am.
- 你好 - 你好 牛仔们
- Ma'am. - Howdy, cowboys.
人多得可真要命
Stone the bloody crows!
那儿想必有同性恋的酒吧
That must've been one of those poofter bars.
对 我奉"同性之爱"为信条 这就是为什么称他为 "男校学生"的原因吧
Yup. Only I believe the correct term is "gay homosexual. "
要钱还是要命?
Give it up, punk, or I'll blow you away.
等等 我听不太清楚
Uh, hang on. I can't hear you.
- 现在好多了 有什么要帮忙的吗? - 有两下子嘛
- That's better. Now how can I help you? - Smart-ass cowboy, huh?
- 钱交出来! - 他们不是牛仔
- Hand me over your money, man! - They ain't cowboys.
- 看这身可笑的打扮 - 笨蛋把钱交出来!
- They're fools dressed up! - Fools got money too.
- 交出来! 否则有你好看的! - 快! 蠢驴!
- Give it up or I'll bust a cap in your ass! - Yeah, hand it over, bitch!
当遇到大莽蛇的时候 你觉得该怎么办?
Son, you have any idea how quick you have to be to catch a tiger snake?
我常被强劫 看来我像个富翁
I'm always getting mugged. I must look rich.
这软蓬跑车不错 扑上去试试
It's one of them soft-top cars. Cave in.
- 嗷 - 怪不得人们称洛杉矶为"车轮之城"
- Ow! - You know, this must be why they call L. A. the "City on Wheels. "
此话怎讲?
What do you mean?
他们连杀人都不必离开车厢
They don't even get out of their car to mug you.
- 嘿 - 嗷
- Hey! - Ow!
都你是你错 笨蛋! 你不应该叫他"蠢驴"!
It's all your fault, homes! You shouldn't have called him a bitch!
要叫警察来吗?
Should we call the cops?
别忙 他们会求饶的
No point. Over here, they'd probably end up suing us.
再说 这也不能全怪他们
Besides, it's not their fault.
他们吸了毒吧
It's the drugs.
我在杰拉尔多 瑞弗拉的节目上看过
I saw all about it on that Geraldo Rivera.
他挺知底细的
He knows the streets.
我们回家前先喝杯咖啡吧?
Let's just get a cup of coffee and go home.
别点得太草率
Don't be too hasty ordering coffee around here.
可能服务态度不太周到
You might not be too happy with the way they serve it.
信我的
Trust me.
看 这就是鳄鱼在他右腿咬下的齿痕
And this is where a big crocodile almost bit his leg right off.
- 哇 - 厉害
- Whoa! - Neat!
实话告诉你们 这还不算大的呢
Well, to tell the truth, kids, it wasn't really that big.
还没20英尺大
No more than 20 feet or so anyway.
哇! 庞然大物!
Whoa! That's huge!
我明白的
Yes, I know.
他们一点专业水平都没有 我也很想揍他
They just don't appreciate a real artiste. I'd have bit him too.
我觉得你才是迷人的
I thought you were fabulous.
我才懒得理导演的话 他是个笨蛋
I don't care what that director said. He's an idiot.
你干得真棒
You were really good.
- 你要净咖啡加一颗糖 对吧? - 啊 谢谢
- You said black with one sugar, right? - Oh, yes.
- 伙计 谢谢 太好了 - 此外...
- Thanks, mate. Excellent. - And...
我也为它准备了一根香蕉
I got us a little treat for our friend here.
真棒! 它爱死了
Oh, great. That'll hit the spot.
净咖啡加一颗糖
Black and one sugar.
它今天脾气有点乖戾
She's a bit grumpy today.
不太喜欢载它的车
Not happy with the size of her trailer.
它要一辆维吉尔那种的 不过我跟她说
She wants a big one like Virgil, but I keep telling her,
"维吉尔是狮子坐的 你是猴子呀"
"Virgil's a lion. You're only a monkey. "
抱歉
Sorry.
"小猩猩"
"Chimpanzee. "
你有想过换经理人吗?
Say, have you thought about changing agents?
伙计 你在跟猩猩说话 它们听不懂英语的
Diego, you're talking to a chimp. They don't speak English.
我前妻也不会说
Neither did my first wife.
努力呀 德瓦沃斯
Keep moving, Dravos.
别笨手笨脚的! 小心对这些画
Don't be stupid! Mind the painting!
按次序将画靠墙斜放
Just lean it carefully against the wall for now.
小心!
Carefully!
你好 菲尔有什么事吗?
G'day, Phil. What's happening, mate?
你好 米克 真是连续不断的恶梦
Hi, Mick. The usual continuity nightmare.
是呀
Right.
- 这话是什么意思? - 是说我必须把这些布景...
- What's that mean? - It means I have to make this set...
弄得像真的置身于南斯拉夫一样
look exactly like it did on location in Yugoslavia.
南斯拉夫? 这些画是从那来的吗?
Yugoslavia. Is that where all these paintings come from?
对 就是在那制作的
Yup. They had them done there. Dumb.
为啥不在这干呢? 既经济又实惠
Would've been cheaper here, and more realistic.
那这些复制品没多大用处了吧?
Oh, so none of these are valuable. They're just all copies.
是的 这些做工不好
Yup, and rather poor ones at that.
看见这幅大而庸俗的构图没? 叫"因主之名"
And these huge, tacky frames? For God sakes.
他们常常用车运这么布景和道具来吗?
Don't they usually cart the sets and the props...
在两个国家之前来回穿梭?
from one country to another and back again?
可能是像"碟中碟3" 那样的制作吧
Maybe in a big-budget international movie like Mission: Impossible 3.
但我可没见过 汤姆 克鲁斯半吊在布景上
But I haven't seen Tom Cruise hanging around the set, have you?
汤姆.克鲁斯长什么样呀?
Tom Cruise. What's he look like?
就像...汤姆.克鲁斯呀
Like... Tom Cruise.
天呀 米克 你不是 出生在荒山野岭的吧?
Jeez, Mick, were you born in a cave?
对呀 你怎么知道的?
Yeah! How did you know that?
抱歉
Never mind.
吉姆 凡高的画排错顺序了
Jim, the Van Goghs are down at the wrong end.
你看 应该从高卢时期排年份排下去吧
See, here they started with the Gauguins, one above the other.
不能有半点差池 今晚就要用了
Let's get this right. We gotta be done in here tonight.
明天早上在这拍摄
They're shooting in here tomorrow.
你看 可洛因是可以和石灰混在一起
You see, you can mix heroin into a plaster,
然后做成任何形状
make it any shape you like.
所以当有人碰撞布景板时 便被臭骂了
So, when I see this guy go nuts 'cause they bumped the lousy painting,
毒品就是这样被铸成镜框的样子
that's when I knew where the drugs were hidden...
被神不知鬼不觉地藏起来
molded into the picture frames.
这就是纯海洛因 俗话说的"白粉"的
Pure heroin, or as we call it, "smack."
米克 你可真像个侦探
Jeez, Mick, you really do think like a detective.
这是天赋的本能 你知道吗?
Yeah, well, it comes sort of natural to me, you know?
- 米克 - 嘿
- Hey, Mick. - Ah.
警方的实验室出报告了
That was the police lab.
很抱歉 画框是石膏做的 并没有毒品
Sorry. The frames are just plaster. There's no drugs.
怎么可能
Oh, bugger it.
我坚信我已经破了这宗案件
I was sure I cracked the case.
难说 可能他们根本没有走私吧
I don't know. Maybe they're not smuggling anything.
不 他们确实偷偷运输一些东西
Oh, no. They're sneaking around with something.
是我还没找出来吧
I just haven't found it yet.
我一眼不看穿他了
Look, I read about this fella,
他常常推着一车牛粪
he used to push a wheelbarrow full of cow dung...
每天越过边境
across the border every day.
他常说"这是花园所需的肥料" 一直相安无事
"Manure for the garden, " he'd say. Went on for months.
海关深信他一定有在走私
And the border guards knew he was smuggling something,
他们停住车 用铁犁仔细在粪里搜寻
so they'd stop him and rake through that manure with a fine-tooth comb.
却一无所获
Never found a thing.
证明了他们的推断是正确的 他确实在走么:
Turned out they were right. He was smuggling something:
他走私手推车
wheelbarrows.
就在海关的眼皮底下
Right under their noses.
因此 即使我找不到任何罪证 我还将坚持下去
See, it's there, and I'm just not seeing it... yet. But I will.
我第一次由衷地信任他: 他们确实在贩毒
Nah. I reckon he was right the first time. It's drugs.
因为走私手推车实在太麻烦了
They wouldn't go to all that trouble for wheelbarrows.
停! 拷贝!
Cut! And print.
我们得删掉他扔东西的场景 这样合适点
We'll cut when he throws, so that'll work fine.
- 好的 - 保罗 干得好
- All right! - Well done, Paul.
诸位听着 我们现在不能把城堡烧掉
Listen, everyone, we do not burn down the castle now.
因为明天还要在这多拍一次
That will be a second-unit shot tomorrow.
因此请大家早去早回
That means everyone goes home early and has tomorrow off.
- 好的 - 星期五见
- Whoo! All right! - Okay, see you all Friday!
第一场!
First thing!
你一直不厌其烦地端祥着这些画
And you've actually seen these paintings quite recently.
不错
Yeah, today.
很明显 这些都是赝品
Well, then that makes it easy. They're fakes.
你怎么看得出来?
You can tell that from the photographs?
一般来说很难说 但看这些伦布兰特的画
Well, normally, no. But, you see, these Rembrandts...
和这幅凡高的"橄榄麦田"
and this, The Olive Field by Van Gogh,
在北约轰炸贝尔格莱德之后
unfortunately no longer exist.
都已经失传了
During the bombing of Belgrade by NATO,
塞尔维亚的自然艺术博物馆惨遭损毁
the National Art Museum of Serbia took a direct hit,
这些原件和东欧...
burned to the ground along with the originals of these paintings...
最有价值的画都已付诸一炬了
and possibly the finest collection of old masters in Eastern Europe.
这真是艺术史上的悲剧
It was a tragedy for the art world.
因此这些必定是赝品
Ergo, these must be copies, fakes.
贝尔格莱德是在南斯拉夫的吗?
That, um, Belgrade, is that in Yugoslavia?
- 是的 - 这些画就是从那儿来的
- Yeah. - Where these paintings come from.
如果这不是误迷途炸的话
What if it wasn't an accidental bombing...
会不会事前已经有人把这些画转移了?
and someone removed the paintings first?
这也是战利品之一?
Spoils of war?
也许我该亲眼看一下 你能带我去吗?
Maybe I should take a look at these. Could you take me to them?
我想不行
That's probably impossible.
不过我能偷一幅来让你鉴定一下
But if I could get one of them and bring it to you and it was real,
窥一斑而知全豹 对不?
that means the rest are probably real, right?
一拿到马上通知我 我一定要看看
You must call me the minute you find one. I have to see them.
- 放心吧 谢谢 - 谢谢
- No worries. Thank you. - Thank you.
- 这是谁画的? - 帕布鲁 毕加索
- Hey, who drew this? - Pablo Picasso.
虽说我也是个酒鬼 不过也不至于伤成这样
I'm a drinking man myself, but I've never been that hammered.
这种小伎俩对我来说小菜一碟
This'll be a piece of cake. I know this lot backwards.
- 在车上等我 - 米克
- Wait in the car. - Uh, Mick?
我想说: "千万小心呀"
I was gonna say, "Be careful, "
不过我想这句话对 猎鳄勇士来说简直是侮辱
but I guess that's kind of a dumb thing to say to someone who hunts crocodiles.
放心吧
No worries.
这样看真是有云泥之别
Of course the difference is obvious here,
但它们在电影是绝佳布景
but on film, it's a perfect match.
- 不是吗? - 太好了 这些画是属于我们的
- Isn't it? - All right, we have the paintings.
现在我们还得在电影圈里耗着吗?
Now must we continue with this stupid movie business bullshit?
你一点都不想吗?
You really don't get it, do you?
细节才是关键
God is in the details.
它们是作为道具运到这来的 谁都想看看它们
These came into the country as film props. Anyone wants to see them...
"很遗憾 我们烧掉了"
"Sorry. We burned them.
"想鉴赏吗? 看电影去吧"
Want proof? Go see the movie."
想看真迹? 门都没有
Dead end. Brilliant.
卡尔 我需要你的帮忙
Carl, we need your help.
卡尔 那幅画要封装好
Carl, that painting should be covered.
我等下来帮你
I'll be with you in a moment.
- 那个人在干嘛? - 抓住他!
- Then who the hell is that? - Stop him!
跟着他! 快!
After him! Quickly!
躲低点! 别误打到画上!
Shoot low! Don't hit the painting!
跟着他! 锁门!
After him! Seal off the lot!
- 快! 接着这个! - 什么?
- Quick! Hold this! Thanks. - What?
他向这边跑了德瓦沃斯跟了上去
He ran in here. Dravos followed him.
关上所有大门 快去帮德瓦沃斯
Cover all the exits. Go in and help Dravos flush him out.
别作声 米克叫我在这等的
Shh. I know, I know. Mick said to wait here.
不必担心
It's his bust, right?
是的 我在看着呢
I know. I was just looking.
你怎么来的? 谁看着迈基?
How'd you get here anyway? Who's looking after Mikey?
他的老师玛菲斯小姐
Miss Mathis, his teacher from school.
我驾她的车跟来的
I followed you in her car.
给你点悬念
Oh. I'll just keep you on hold.
啊
Ah.
这悬念不错吧哈 我要出去会合他们了
Keep you on hold. Ha! I just come out with them.
- 那个男的是谁? 为什么他? - 我想是那个耍猴人
- Who is this man? How does he... - I think he's the monkey guy.
驯猴人米克 他们的帽子相同
Mick, the guy that trains the monkey. Same hat.
驯猴的怎么会知道画的事情?
How would the monkey guy know about the paintings?
就他一个? 你最好祈祷他还活着
Is he alone? You better hope he's still alive.
进去吧
Get in there.
我们在第四层
We're entering stage four.
- 我们向你那边追去 - 罗格那边
- We'll flush him your way. - Roger that.
噢
Oh!
射低点 要留活口
Shoot low. We need him alive.
小心呐
Watch out...
就说有墙嘛
for the wall.
他到丛林景区那边去了
He's gone to the jungle set.
那只有一扇门
There's only one way in and out of there.
- 我到门前了 - 在我们赶到以前看牢他
- I'm on it. - Cover the gate till we get there.
嘿! 嘿! 嘿! 嘿!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
大获全胜
High five.
斯坦 老板说不要独自进入那儿
Stan, copy. Boss said don't go in there alone.
- 斯坦? 斯坦? - 太迟了 伙计
- Stan? Stan? - Too late, mate.
斯坦!
Stan!
竟然这样 呃
Did it, um...
我想它没有插中吧
I- It... missed, I think.
但愿如此
I hope.
米克
Hi, Mick.
我知道你还在这
I know you're still here.
我们停止这个愚蠢的游戏吧?
Why don't we stop playing this silly game?
你出来
You can come out and...
和你的朋友一起
join your friends.
我可没耐心和你耗下去
I have no more patience for this!
好吧 我这就出来
Okay, you win. I'm comin' out.
不要乱动
Just don't make any sudden moves.
不要这么客气嘛 大家都是朋友
You don't have to be so formal. We're all friends.
你可以放下双手
You can... lower your hands.
我这只手动不了
I can't really lower this one.
- 为什么? - 如果我手垂下来
- And why is that? - 'Cause if I put this arm down...
就会破坏我们之间的眼神交流了
and break eye contact,
他会离开这儿 并将你们分尸
he might come down here and tear you apart.
- 谁? - 就是住在那的家伙
- Who? - Fella who lives in there.
看 就在岩石后面
Look. Up on the rock.
你们真差劲 三八手枪杀不了一只狮子吗?
Are you nuts? Can't kill a lion with a. 38pistol.
如果你打伤任何人 那最好不要流血
If you shoot anyone, they better not bleed.
狮子嗅到血就会狂戾起来
Lions go berserk when they smell blood.
如果我是你 我就乖乖地回到笼子里
If I was you, I'd back up slowly into that cage.
毫无疑问 那是
Uh, yeah. Surely, that's a...
驯化了的狮子
tame lion.
对 你说得对
Yeah. You could be right.
我杀了你 用你的血喂狮子去吧
I shoot you. You bleed.
- 我碰碰运气吧 - 对你而言小菜一碟
- I take my chances. - But he's not your problem.
恐怕他的妻子来了
It's his missus I'm worried about.
我可控制不了它
I can't handle her.
一望可知 她想发飚
She's got PMS, I think. Can see it in her eyes.
你大可随心所欲
Anyway, you do what you have to do.
在它的岳母到来以前
I'm getting in the cage...
我到笼子里去了
before his mother-in-law comes down.
啊! 不!
No! No!
- 把门打开! 把门打开! - 先把枪给我
- Open the door! Open the door now! - Give me the gun.
你竟敢用枪指着我妻子
You held a gun to my wife's head.
- 啊? - 这是不可饶恕的
- Huh? - That's unforgivable.
- 让我来帮你减减肥吧 - 怎么?
- I'm gonna help you lose some weight. - How?
维吉尔要来咬下你屁股的一块肥肉
Virgil's gonna come down here and bite a big chunk out of your fat ass.
维吉尔 你的午餐到了!
Virgil, lunch!
坐下来!
Sit!
如果你敢动我一根毫毛 我要你加倍奉还
If you touch me, I will sue you for every cent you've got.
哈 听上去听挺公平的
Ha! Well, that sounds fair.
嘿 这是40美元
Hey, that's about 40 bucks.
很公平吧?
It's a fair deal.
算是吧
Bargain.
你没事吧?
And how are you, miss?
- 你到底在这干什么? - 嗯 我必须这样
- What the hell were you doing in here? - Well, I had to.
我的手机坏了
My cell phone went dead,
我必须来找个电话报警
and I had to come in here to find a phone to call 911.
苏 我真没有想到原来你是这么聪明的
You're clever, Sue. I never would've thought of that.
当然 因为她是邓迪太太
Yeah, well, that's because she's a Dundee.
或者说她必须是吧
Or she ought to be.
杰科 别过头去 堵上耳朵
Uh, Jacko, keep an eye on the goons and, uh, block your ears.
- 什么? - 堵上耳朵 这是隐私
- What? - Block your ears. Private talk.
好吧
No worries, mate.
我不得不告诉你
Uh, I have to tell you this.
刚刚是我一生中第一次感到害怕
I was just really scared for the first time in my life.
这没什么大不了的 许多人都害怕狮子
Well, that's okay. Most people are frightened of lions.
跟狮子无关 它们只是饿了
No, not the lions. They're just hungry.
我是说当看到那个 浑球用枪指着你的时候
It's when I saw that goon with a gun at your head.
我如此深切地感觉到 嗯
That's when I realized how much I, uh...
你知道的 嗯
You know, um...
请嫁给我吧
Will you marry me?
米克 这太出人意表了吧?
Well, you do rush into things, don't you, Mick?
这个布景可不够浪漫
Are you sure it's not just the romantic setting?
专家认为这些重见天日的艺术品的
Local experts say the value of the recovered art...
价值高达3亿美元
could run as high as $300 million.
最后 现场记者玛塔沃勒 为你进行报道 玛塔?
For the very latest, let's go live to Marta Waller at the scene. Marta?
谢谢海尔 现在警察们正在
Thanks, Hal. Right now the police are taking...
将这些无价之宝搬进保全车
these priceless paintings into protective custody.
现在我身后和侦探在 谈话的是苏 查尔顿小姐
The woman behind me talking to the detective is Ms. Sue Charleton,
她就是带侦探们来这名画匿藏地的
the Newsday reporter...
"今日新闻报"的记者...
who led detectives to the cache of stolen masterpieces.
遗憾的是 抓住窃贼的幕后英雄们...
Unfortunately, the undercover agent who actually capture the thiefs
拒绝接受镜头前的采访
decline to be  interviewered on camera
然而 今晚的较早时候
However, earlier tonight,
他跟我说他是艺术界一个知名的专家拒绝接受镜头前的采访
he did tell me he is, in fact, a known expert in the art world.
就是那个在高速公路上 造成大堵车的家伙吗?
Isn't that the guy who had the skunk on the freeway?
- 海尔! - 接下来还有很多精彩的新闻
- Hey, Hal! - We'll have more as the story unfolds.
现在让我们来看看来自马利布地区的消息
Right now let's go to Malibu...
昨晚的倾盆大雨为该地区带来1/4英寸的降水
where last night's downpour of almost a quarter inch of rain...
造成洪灾和太平洋海岸高速公路的
resulted in disastrous flooding and massive mud slides...
山泥寸泻
along the Pacific Coast Highway.
苏 你愿意接受这个恶棍
Sue, do you accept this larrikin...
为你的合法丈夫?
as your wedded husband?
- 我愿意 - 米克
- I do. - Mick,
你愿意接受这可爱的女士 为你的合法妻子吗?
do you accept this lovely lady as your wedded wife?
毫无疑问
No worries.
相当公平 我现在郑重宣布
Fair enough. I now pronounce you...
你们结为合法夫妻
husband and wife.
- 干得好 米克 - 太棒了!
- Good on ya, Mick. - All right!
现在你可以名正言顺地说 你是"米克 邓迪第二"了
It's official now, mate. You're Mick Dundee II.
- 太棒了! - 现在让我们来期待着
- Cool. - Now I guess we'll wait and see...
你如何成为为另一个"鳄鱼邓迪"
whether you turn out to be another Crocodile Dundee...
或报界大亨迈克尔 邓迪
or Michael Dundee, newspaper tycoon.
这显而易见 爸
Oh, that's a no-brainer, Dad.
我当然是要成为"鳄鱼邓迪"
I'm gonna be Crocodile Dundee,
猎人和报界大亨
hunter and rich owner of a big newspaper.
我可不是傻瓜
I didn't raise a dumbbell.
戴上这个来照相吧
Put this on for the photos.
- 为啥? - 你穿上西装像个笨蛋
- What for? - You look like a dork in that suit.
- 不用了吧 - 你必须穿得像"鳄鱼邓迪"呀
- No, I don't. - You should look like Crocodile Dundee.
我的猎鳄时光一去不复返了
No, I think my crocodile huntin' days are over.
从今天开始 我是"私家侦探: 米克邓迪先生"
From here on in, it's... "Mick Dundee, Private Eye. "
不 我在开玩笑呢
Nah. I'm kiddin'.
# I come from a land down under #
# The beer does flow and men chunder #
# Can't you hear can't you hear that thunder #
# You better run You better take cover, yeah #
# raveling in a fried-out combie #
# On a hippie trail Head full of zombie #
# I met a strange lady #
# She made me nervous #
# She took me in and gave me breakfast #
# She said do you come from a land down under #
# Where women glow and men plunder #
# Can 't you hear can 't you hear the thunder #
# You better run You better take cover, yeah #
# Buying bread from a man in Brussels #
# He was six foot four and full of muscles #
# I said do you speak my language, brother #
# He just smiled and gave me a Vegemite sandwich #
# He said I come from a land down under #
# Where beer does flow and men chunder #
# Can 't you hear can 't you hear the thunder #
# You better run You better take cover, yeah #
# Lying in a den in Bombay #
# With a slack jaw and not a lot to say #
# I said to the man Are you trying to tempt me #
# Because I come from the land of plenty #